<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>WireGuard on Michael Schnerring</title><link>https://schnerring.net/tags/wireguard/</link><description>Recent content in WireGuard on Michael Schnerring</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>© 2020 - 2023 Michael Schnerring</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 04:53:09 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://schnerring.net/tags/wireguard/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Use Mullvad Port Forwarding to Connect to Your OPNsense Home Network with WireGuard</title><link>https://schnerring.net/blog/use-mullvad-port-forwarding-to-connect-to-your-opnsense-home-network-with-wireguard/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2021 21:18:30 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://schnerring.net/blog/use-mullvad-port-forwarding-to-connect-to-your-opnsense-home-network-with-wireguard/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="update-2023-07-28">Update 2023-07-28&lt;a href="#update-2023-07-28" class="post-heading__anchor" aria-hidden="true">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a
 href="https://mullvad.net/en/blog/2023/5/29/removing-the-support-for-forwarded-ports/"
 
 
 class="link--external" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer"
 
>In May 2023, Mullvad announced the discontinuation of port forwarding support.&lt;/a> Starting from 2023-07-01, all existing ports will be removed, making this guide obsolete. 😭&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>OPNsense Baseline Guide with Mullvad VPN Multi-WAN, Guest, and VLAN Support</title><link>https://schnerring.net/blog/opnsense-baseline-guide-with-vpn-guest-and-vlan-support/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 03:56:35 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://schnerring.net/blog/opnsense-baseline-guide-with-vpn-guest-and-vlan-support/</guid><description>This beginner-friendly, step-by-step guide walks you through the initial configuration of your OPNsense firewall. The title of this guide is an homage to the pfSense baseline guide with VPN, Guest, and VLAN support that some of you guys might know, and this is an OPNsense migration of it. I found that guide two years ago and immediately fell in love with the network setup. After researching for weeks, I decided to use OPNsense instead of pfSense.</description></item><item><title>Use Custom DNS Servers With Mullvad And Any WireGuard Client</title><link>https://schnerring.net/blog/use-custom-dns-servers-with-mullvad-and-any-wireguard-client/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2021 08:19:52 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://schnerring.net/blog/use-custom-dns-servers-with-mullvad-and-any-wireguard-client/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Mullvad VPN for a while now but only ever used it with the official client on my workstation. I use DNS extensively in my home network, so as soon as I activate Mullvad, I can&amp;rsquo;t resolve DNS names locally. Of course, this is by design and expected. I own an OPNsense appliance, so the natural solution is to move the tunnel there.
TL;DR# Use the following shell command to request an IP with no DNS hijacking:</description></item></channel></rss>